https://www.easystepstairlifts.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
This privacy policy applies between you, the User of this Website and Easystep Stairlifts Ltd, the owner and provider of this Website. Easystep Stairlifts Ltd takes the privacy of your information very seriously. This privacy policy applies to our use of any and all Data collected by us or provided by you in relation to your use of the Website.This privacy policy should be read alongside, and in addition to, our Terms and Conditions, which can be found at: https://www.easystepstairlifts.co.uk/terms-and-conditions. Please read this privacy policy carefully. Definitions and interpretation 1. In this privacy policy, the following definitions are used: Data collectively all information that you submit to Easystep Stairlifts Ltd via the Website. This definition incorporates, where applicable, the definitions provided in the Data Protection Laws; Cookies a small text file placed on your computer by this Website when you visit certain parts of the Website and/or when you use certain features of the Website. Details of the cookies used by this Website are set out in the clause below (Cookies);Data Protection Laws any applicable law relating to the processing of personal Data, including but not limited to the Directive 96/46/EC (Data Protection Directive) or the GDPR, and any national implementing laws, regulations and secondary legislation, for as long as the GDPR is effective in the UK;GDPR the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679;Easystep Stairlifts Ltd, or us Easystep Stairlifts Ltd, a company incorporated in England and Wales with registered number Suite 2 Rosehill whose registered office is at 165 Lutterworth Road, Blaby, Leicestershire, LE8 4DY;UK and EU Cookie Law the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 as amended by the Privacy and Electronxic Communications (EC Directive) (Amendment) Regulations 2011;User or you any third party that accesses the Website and is not either (i) employed by Easystep Stairlifts Ltd and acting in the course of their employment or (ii) engaged as a consultant or otherwise providing services to Easystep Stairlifts Ltd and accessing the Website in connection with the provision of such services; andWebsite the website that you are currently using, www.easystepstairlifts.co.uk, and any sub-domains of this site unless expressly excluded by their own terms and conditions. 2. In this privacy policy, unless the context requires a different interpretation: a. the singular includes the plural and vice versa;b. references to sub-clauses, clauses, schedules or appendices are to sub-clauses, clauses, schedules or appendices of this privacy policy;c. a reference to a person includes firms, companies, government entities, trusts and partnerships;d. “including” is understood to mean “including without limitation”;e. reference to any statutory provision includes any modification or amendment of it;f. the headings and sub-headings do not form part of this privacy policy. Scope of this privacy policy3. This privacy policy applies only to the actions of Easystep Stairlifts Ltd and Users with respect to this Website. It does not extend to any websites that can be accessed from this Website including, but not limited to, any links we may provide to social media websites. 4. For purposes of the applicable Data Protection Laws, Easystep Stairlifts Ltd is the “data controller”. This means that Easystep Stairlifts Ltd determines the purposes for which, and the manner in which, your Data is processed. Data collected5. We may collect the following Data, which includes personal Data, from you: a. name;b. contact Information such as email addresses and telephone numbers;c. in each case, in accordance with this privacy policy. How we collect Data6. We collect Data in the following ways: a. data is given to us by you; andb. data is collected automatically. Data that is given to us by you7. Easystep Stairlifts Ltd will collect your Data in a number of ways, for example: a. when you contact us through the Website, by telephone, post, e-mail or through any other means;b. when you make payments to us, through this Website or otherwise;c. when you elect to receive marketing communications from us;d. when you use our services;in each case, in accordance with this privacy policy. Data that is collected automatically8. To the extent that you access the Website, we will collect your Data automatically, for example: a. we automatically collect some information about your visit to the Website. This information helps us to make improvements to Website content and navigation, and includes your IP address, the date, times and frequency with which you access the Website and the way you use and interact with its content.b. we will collect your Data automatically via cookies, in line with the cookie settings on your browser. For more information about cookies, and how we use them on the Website, see the section below, headed “Cookies”. Our use of Data9. Any or all of the above Data may be required by us from time to time in order to provide you with the best possible service and experience when using our Website. Specifically, Data may be used by us for the following reasons: a. internal record keeping;in each case, in accordance with this privacy policy. 10. We may use your Data for the above purposes if we deem it necessary to do so for our legitimate interests. If you are not satisfied with this, you have the right to object in certain circumstances (see the section headed “Your rights” below). Keeping Data secure11. We will use technical and organisational measures to safeguard your Data, for example: a. access to your account is controlled by a password and a user name that is unique to you.b. we store your Data on secure servers. 12. Technical and organisational measures include measures to deal with any suspected data breach. If you suspect any misuse or loss or unauthorised access to your Data, please let us know immediately by contacting us via this e-mail address: info@easystepstairlifts.co.uk. 13. If you want detailed information from Get Safe Online on how to protect your information and your computers and devices against fraud, identity theft, viruses and many other online problems, please visit www.getsafeonline.org. Get Safe Online is supported by HM Government and leading businesses. Data retention14. Unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law, we will only hold your Data on our systems for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this privacy policy or until you request that the Data be deleted. 15. Even if we delete your Data, it may persist on backup or archival media for legal, tax or regulatory purposes.Your rights 16. You have the following rights in relation to your Data: a. Right to access – the right to request (i) copies of the information we hold about you at any time, or (ii) that we modify, update or delete such information. If we provide you with access to the information we hold about you, we will not charge you for this, unless your request is “manifestly unfounded or excessive.” Where we are legally permitted to do so, we may refuse your request. If we refuse your request, we will tell you the reasons why.b. Right to correct – the right to have your Data rectified if it is inaccurate or incomplete.c. Right to erase – the right to request that we delete or remove your Data from our systems.d. Right to restrict our use of your Data – the right to “block” us from using your Data or limit the way in which we can use it.e. Right to data portability – the right to request that we move, copy or transfer your Data.f. Right to object – the right to object to our use of your Data including where we use it for our legitimate interests. 17. To make enquiries, exercise any of your rights set out above, or withdraw your consent to the processing of your Data (where consent is our legal basis for processing your Data), please contact us via this e-mail address: info@easystepstairlifts.co.uk. 18. If you are not satisfied with the way a complaint you make in relation to your Data is handled by us, you may be able to refer your complaint to the relevant data protection authority. For the UK, this is the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO). The ICO’s contact details can be found on their website at https://ico.org.uk/. 19. It is important that the Data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your Data changes during the period for which we hold it. Links to other websites20. This Website may, from time to time, provide links to other websites. We have no control over such websites and are not responsible for the content of these websites. This privacy policy does not extend to your use of such websites. You are advised to read the privacy policy or statement of other websites prior to using them. Changes of business ownership and control21. Easystep Stairlifts Ltd may, from time to time, expand or reduce our business and this may involve the sale and/or the transfer of control of all or part of Easystep Stairlifts Ltd. Data provided by Users will, where it is relevant to any part of our business so transferred, be transferred along with that part and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this privacy policy, be permitted to use the Data for the purposes for which it was originally supplied to us. 22. We may also disclose Data to a prospective purchaser of our business or any part of it. 23. In the above instances, we will take steps with the aim of ensuring your privacy is protected.Cookies 24. This Website may place and access certain Cookies on your computer. Easystep Stairlifts Ltd uses Cookies to improve your experience of using the Website and to improve our range of products and services. Easystep Stairlifts Ltd has carefully chosen these Cookies and has taken steps to ensure that your privacy is protected and respected at all times. 25. All Cookies used by this Website are used in accordance with current UK and EU Cookie Law. 26. Before the Website places Cookies on your computer, you will be presented with a message bar requesting your consent to set those Cookies. By giving your consent to the placing of Cookies, you are enabling Easystep Stairlifts Ltd to provide a better experience and service to you. You may, if you wish, deny consent to the placing of Cookies; however certain features of the Website may not function fully or as intended. 27. This Website may place the following Cookies:Type of Cookie PurposeAnalytical/performance cookies They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily. 28. You can find a list of Cookies that we use in the Cookies Schedule. 29. You can choose to enable or disable Cookies in your internet browser. By default, most internet browsers accept Cookies but this can be changed. For further details, please consult the help menu in your internet browser. 30. You can choose to delete Cookies at any time; however you may lose any information that enables you to access the Website more quickly and efficiently including, but not limited to, personalisation settings. 31. It is recommended that you ensure that your internet browser is up-to-date and that you consult the help and guidance provided by the developer of your internet browser if you are unsure about adjusting your privacy settings. 32. For more information generally on cookies, including how to disable them, please refer to aboutcookies.org. You will also find details on how to delete cookies from your computer. General33. You may not transfer any of your rights under this privacy policy to any other person. We may transfer our rights under this privacy policy where we reasonably believe your rights will not be affected. 34. If any court or competent authority finds that any provision of this privacy policy (or part of any provision) is invalid, illegal or unenforceable, that provision or part-provision will, to the extent required, be deemed to be deleted, and the validity and enforceability of the other provisions of this privacy policy will not be affected. 35. Unless otherwise agreed, no delay, act or omission by a party in exercising any right or remedy will be deemed a waiver of that, or any other, right or remedy. 36. This Agreement will be governed by and interpreted according to the law of England and Wales. All disputes arising under the Agreement will be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the English and Welsh courts. Changes to this privacy policy37. Easystep Stairlifts Ltd reserves the right to change this privacy policy as we may deem necessary from time to time or as may be required by law. Any changes will be immediately posted on the Website and you are deemed to have accepted the terms of the privacy policy on your first use of the Website following the alterations.You may contact Easystep Stairlifts Ltd by email at info@easystepstairlifts.co.uk. Attribution38. This privacy policy was created 19 July 2018 CookiesBelow is a list of the cookies that we use. We have tried to ensure this is complete and up to date, but if you think that we have missed a cookie or there is any discrepancy, please let us know. Analytical/performanceWe use the following analytical/performance cookies:Description of Cookie PurposeGoogle Analytics We use this cookie to help us analyse how users use the website
Request a quick callback or call us on 0800 0936 911
Name
Email
Phone
Submit
Due to COVID-19 we are now offering a self survey form for straight stairlifts to help keep our customers safe. No salesman visit!
Learn More
×
This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish. Cookie settingsACCEPTPrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.
Necessary
Necessary
Always Enabled
Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non-necessary
Non-necessary
Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
